newbluefx.com 2019-08-30

# Privacy Policy | NewBlueFX

_Last updated: May 21, 2018_

NewBlue recognizes that your privacy is very important and we take it seriously. This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) describes our policies and procedures on the collection, use, disclosure, and sharing of your personal information or personal data when you use the NewBlue Products. This Privacy Policy applies to activities by NewBlue, Inc. and its affiliates and subsidiaries (collectively “NewBlue,” “we” or “us”). Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given to them in our Terms of Service.

### **The Information We Collect**

We collect only the information we need to process your sale and provide product support: your name, e-mail address, mailing address and phone number, and products purchased. At time of purchase, you may also indicate a preference to receive product update information and offers.

Once collected, we will not disclose this information to third parties (unless we are required to do so by law) and will protect this information in accordance with our strict security and confidentiality standards. We do not offer or allow the selling of any user provided information to third parties.

If after purchase you no longer desire our services, you can correct, update or remove the personal data provided to us by logging on to our Support system and editing or deleting your Personal Profile.

If you bought our product through an affiliate, they also received this information through the purchase process, and you should check their privacy policy. We only work with reputable affiliates who ascribe to trustworthy standards.

Finally, the address and product purchase information is provided to us by our electronic commerce provider, FastSpring. You can read their privacy policy at <https://fastspring.com/privacy>

###  **Correcting / Updating Personal Information**

If your personal information changes (such as your zip code), or if you no longer desire our services, you can correct, update or remove the personal data provided to us. You may also choose to opt in or out of our product update option at any time.

### To change your personal information, log into your account and edit your Personal Profile or submit a request at support@newblueinc.com. ****

******How We Use Your Information**

We do not sell your personal data – such as your name and contact information – to third parties to use for their own marketing purposes. NewBlue uses the information we collect for the following purposes:

  * Provide our Services. To provide you the Products we offer on the NewBlue website, communicate with you about your use of the NewBlue Products, respond to your inquiries, provide troubleshooting, and for other customer service purposes.

  * Personalization. To tailor the content and information that we may send you, including personalized help and instructions, and to otherwise personalize your experiences.

  * Marketing and Promotions. For marketing and promotional purposes, such as to send you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions, or to otherwise contact you about products or information we think may interest you, including information about third party products and services.

  * Analytics. To gather metrics to better understand how users access and use the NewBlue products; to evaluate and improve NewBlue Products, and to develop new products and services.

  * Comply with Law. To comply with legal obligations, as part of our general business operations, and for other business administration purposes.

  * Prevent Misuse. Where we believe necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person or violations of our Terms of Service or this Privacy Policy.

### **  
How We Share Your Information**

We share information as set forth below, and where individuals have otherwise consented:

_**Service Providers.**_  We may share your information with third party service providers who use this information to perform services for us, such as payment processors, hosting providers, auditors, advisors, consultants, customer service and support providers.

_**Affiliates**_. The information collected about you may be accessed by or shared with subsidiaries and affiliates of NewBlue, Inc., whose use and disclosure of your personal information is subject to this Privacy Policy.

_**Business Transfers.  **_We may disclose or transfer information, including personal information, as part of any merger, sale, and transfer of our assets, acquisition or restructuring of all or part of our business, bankruptcy, or similar event.

_**Legally Required.**_  We may disclose your information if we are required to do so by law.

_**Protection of Rights.  **_We may disclose information where we believe it necessary to respond to claims asserted against us or, comply with legal process (e.g., subpoenas or warrants), enforce or administer our agreements and terms, for fraud prevention, risk assessment, investigation, and protect the rights, property or safety of NewBlue, its users, or others.

_**Anonymized and Aggregated Data.**_  We may share aggregated or de-identified information with third parties for research, marketing, analytics and other purposes, provided such information does not identify a particular individual.

### **Cookies, Pixels and Tracking**

We and our third party providers use cookies, clear GIFs/pixel tags, JavaScript, local storage, log files, and other mechanisms to automatically collect and record information about your usage. We may combine this information with other information we collect about users. Below, we provide a brief summary these activities. For more detailed information about these mechanisms and how we collect activity information, see our Cookie Policy.

  * _Cookies_. These are small files with a unique identifier that are transferred to your browser through our websites. They allow us to understand how users navigate through NewBlue website.

  * _Pixels, web beacons, clear GIFs_. These are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. We also use these in our emails to let us know when they have been opened or clicked, so we can gauge the effectiveness of our communications.

  * _Analytics Tools._  We may use internal and third party analytics tools, including [Google Analytics](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en). The third party analytics companies we work with may combine the information collected with other information they have independently collected from other websites and/or other online products and services. Their collection and use of information is subject to their own privacy policies. 

**How We Protect Your Information**

The security of your information is important to us. NewBlue has implemented safeguards to protect the information we collect. However, no website or Internet transmission is completely secure. We urge you to take steps to keep your personal information safe, such as choosing a strong password and keeping it private, as well as logging out of your user account, and closing your web browser when finished using the NewBlue website.

NewBlue does not have access to your credit card or other payment information, which is handled through FastSpring. FastSpring protects your transaction with the strongest exportable standards of encryption.

FastSpring’s security policy is included as a link on your order, so you may review it before completing your transaction.

NewBlue also does everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our sales representatives, marketing personnel or customer service representatives) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers’ information is protected. Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment.

**Third Party Ad Networks**

For information about and to opt out of interest-based ads from many ad networks, go to:

  * U.S.: [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) Internet Advertising Bureau

  * Canada: [www.youradchoices.ca](http://www.youradchoices.ca/)

  * European Union: [www.youronlinechoices.eu/](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

**Cookies**

A cookie is a piece of data that identifies you as a unique user. The cookies we use do not collect personal identification information, and we do not use them to determine your identity.

We use cookies to facilitate your product purchase and support requests through our help ticket system. We also may use cookies to improve the quality of our service and to understand our user base.

If you are not comfortable with this use, you may configure your browser so you are notified when cookies are to be received and to provide you with the option of refusing cookies. However, refusing cookies may limit your ability to use our Web site in its entirety.

Some of our business partners may use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to, or control over, these cookies.

**Log Files**

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track users’ movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Links to Other Websites**

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, NewBlue, are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personal identification information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Children’s Privacy**

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 (or under the age of 14 for anyone living in Spain or South Korea) or knowingly allow such persons to register. If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under the relevant age without parental consent, we take steps to delete that information.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

California law permits users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, a list of the third parties to whom we have disclosed their personal information (if any) for their direct marketing purposes in the prior calendar year, as well as the types of personal information disclosed to those parties. If you are a California resident and would like to request this information, please submit your request in an email to privacy@newblueinc.com

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions about our practices or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at privacy@newblueinc.com, or send mail to:

NewBlue, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy  
3900 5th Ave, Suite 280  
San Diego, CA 92103

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on this page. If we make any changes to this Privacy Policy that materially change how we treat your personal information, we will endeavor to provide you with reasonable notice of such changes, such as via prominent notice in the NewBlue Products or to your email address of record, and where required by law, we will obtain your consent or give you the opportunity to opt out of such changes.
